<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>scientiac::syntropy - Eerie</title>
    <subtitle>A Computer Engineering student who loves FOSS and is learning about privacy, the Internet and languages writing about the things he does.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://scientiac.space/series/eerie/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://scientiac.space/series/eerie/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Eerie: Floating</title>
        <published>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/eerie-2/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/eerie-2/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/eerie-2/">&lt;em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I slowly open my eyes, but, all I can see is a hole just above my head from where a bright light is entering the room.
Slowly, I turn my head and look around, there&#x27;s a table, or something that resembles a table.
The colour is brown and has patches of lichens all around and on it there is a grey mug with greenish liquid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I slowly get up from the floor and look around, the room is small and it is entirely covered by a
green moss and had radiant yellow flowers. I touch the table and it was cold and rough.
I tried to pick up the mug, it was heavy, it was carved out of stone.
As soon as I picked it up, I heard a screeching sound and a bright light appeared from an opening
that just formed on the floor. I sipped the liquid and it was just water, I drank it all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slipping through the opening on the floor I got outside the room. Everything was bright,
my eyes teared up, I rubbed my eyes and opened them again. As my eyes adjusted to the light, I look ahead.
Big plateaued hills of different shapes floating in air, the top of the plateau was full of what looks
like trees and plants. Around the walls of the hills were intricate paths, structured like a balcony,
hanging by what looks like strings. I see the sun, midst the floating hills with a yellow glow of warmth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I start to walk and as I walk It feels like I am approaching the edge. I don&#x27;t have to assume
to know that I am also on one of the floating plateaus. As I keep walking I am out of the shadow
cast by one of the plateau, I feel the warmth of the sun, it is comforting but It doesn&#x27;t help with
the feeling that I am all alone there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am mesmerized with the view from the edge. Suddenly my stomach growls, it feels like I haven&#x27;t eaten in days.
I see a way going down from the edge, and as I walk It just feels like I am walking on the side of a hill.
I keep going down. If it was a hill, I would expect a river on the bottom and an uphill after I crossed the river.
But, there wasn&#x27;t another hill. Without a shade, the walls of the plateau were thriving with green plants, but,
there exists bits and hints of a civilization living there. I keep walking downhill and, far away I see a shed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make it my mission to reach the shade. I am hoping to find some food I can eat there.
I keep walking but as the shed looks closer my hunger starts getting worse, I start feeling more tired.
Sprinting faster, I try to reach the shed sooner but as am walking, something passes through my peripheral vision.
I walk back a few steps and see a creek on the wall of the plateau. I go closer to the wall and splash! I step on water.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was leaking from the crack on the wall. And on the wall I see a small watery ball
hanging by the root of a plant. I pluck it off the root and drop it in the puddle near my leg which I would have
completely missed if I had not looked back sprinting toward the shed. It was shaped with the soil around it
to preserve a scoop-able body of water. I bent down and see a few tadpoles floating on the puddle.
I wash the ball and take a bite, it is watery and a little bitter, so I throw the remaining half it away.
I scoop some water and drink it, it is clear and cold. I wash my face, hands, and legs
, take some rest and start walking again. I get closer to the shed. There is a creature, it looks like a hybrid
of a horse and a dragon. I am astonished. It it tied to its horns and it seems to be domesticated.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with a pile of grass it is also feeding on the same watery balls I had tasted before.
I see a pile of grass beside the shed, it looks like it was gathered there for the creature.
I go there and see a bunch of root-balls, so I decide to eat them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Eerie: Separation</title>
        <published>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/eerie-1/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/eerie-1/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/eerie-1/">&lt;em&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there I was, in the sky. Being flown uncontrollably with the wind&#x27;s will.
The string of a big red balloon in my right hand and the other hand; sore, blistered and in burning pain.
I am shouting, screaming but there&#x27;s no one that can hear me. All I see is the clear blue sky all around me, and a single patch of cloud far away.
I look down, the ocean, all blue, it hurts my head, I feel dizzy.
I look up, a sharp reflection of the white sun burns my eyes while the cold wind keeps drifting, jerking me left and right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t know what time it is. I don&#x27;t know where I am. I don&#x27;t remember where I came from.
All I can feel is an excruciating pain in my arm, my eyes burning and the wind keeps piercing my body with cold.
I switch arms, and hold the string tighter. But, I am slipping, my hand&#x27;s wet with sweat. I don&#x27;t know If I can hold it very long.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Far away, near the horizon, I see something. Something big, approaching toward me. Or, maybe I was approaching it.
I can not describe it the way I saw it but, this is the best description I can give you.
It looked like the sky had divided the ocean into two halves. The separation looked like two bubbles of soap merging.
The ocean was same, but the water, it felt different. The colour of the sky was same, that of the water was same but, it felt wrong, weird.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get closer and closer and closer. And then all of a sudden I had crossed it. I was at the other half of the earth.
The air was heavy, the water was muddy, the wind colder and the sky was white. It was bright but I couldn&#x27;t find the sun.
The separation drifted further and further away from me. I began to sink. I could see a green patch of land from high above.
I saw two little flowers; a red, and an orange dot. I switch hands again. My neck hurts, my throat is sore. But, I keep shouting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sinking down and as I sink the land got bigger. I could see the waves of grass as the wind glides through the field.
Those weren&#x27;t flowers, they were two little girls sitting on the grass.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help! Hellllllp! I scream! But they can&#x27;t hear me. I keep screaming and finally the girl in the orange sees me.
She stands up, pulls the other girl&#x27;s hand and points toward me. The girl in the red stands up and starts running after me.
I was a little relieved, but as the ground got closer my hand starts to give up.
I hold the string tight with both my hands with all the energy left in me. But as I the ground gets nearer, the harder it gets to hold on.
I put each and every ounce of my strength to it. It&#x27;s getting difficult to sustain.
All of a sudden everything turned dark.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#x27;t feel my breath, I can not see, a constant beep in my ears get louder.
And a flash! The white light faded away as I saw the clouds with blue patches of sky here and there.
Half the sky covered by the green leaves of a rain tree.
I can feel a wet cloth in my forehead. Then, I hear a voice, &quot;Sister! The guy is awake! Come back.&quot;
I try to get up, but I cannot. The girl in the red dress comes near me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can see that she&#x27;s wearing a red gown, it has a pattern of small yellow daisies. I look at her.
Freckles on her cheeks, black eyes, her face is glowing, skin&#x27;s dark and curly black hair that&#x27;s shining brown as the light passes through it.
She is beautiful. She breaks a taro leaf near a puddle, gently folds it, scoops some water in it and asks her sister to slowly lift my head.
I look at her, she is in a plain yellow dress, it has layers of white stripes in the neck and sleeves.
Grey eyes, her skin is bright, hair&#x27;s brown and a small mole on her left cheek just above her dimples as she smiles and gently raises my head.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take a sip of water, it was the best sensation I had ever felt in my whole life. I was alive, I slowly pulled myself up and leaned on the tree trunk.
I look in front of me, it was only grassland spanning up to the horizon. Then the girl in the red gown spoke to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;What is your name?&quot;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I don&#x27;t know.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Where did you come from?&quot;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I don&#x27;t remember.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Do you remember anything?&quot;, she asked.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Trying to think I close my eyes. I clench my fists, grit my teeth and hold my breath in concentration.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
