<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>scientiac::syntropy - Stories</title>
    <subtitle>A Computer Engineering student who loves FOSS and is learning about privacy, the Internet and languages writing about the things he does.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://scientiac.space/writings/stories/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://scientiac.space/writings/stories/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Humans</title>
        <published>2024-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/humans/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/humans/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/humans/">&lt;p&gt;And he said...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We humans are pathetic for hiding our emotions, the only thing that makes us humans.
Nothing is visual, nothing is apparent, nothing is what it seems like it is.
If only it was simple, to understand the person sitting in front of you smiling.
But, we never know what a person is feeling just by asking them.
Yet the words that describe emotions are getting heavier,
I am happy, I am sad, I am unsatisfied, I am confused, I am worried, I am angry, I am sad, I am sad, I am sad, I am at the verge of depression..........&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;important&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p class=&quot;alert-title&quot;&gt;Important&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;If there are italic voices inside &quot;(&lt;em&gt;parenthesis&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&quot; then that it is me talking to myself in my head, feel free to ignore my head.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is even worse in &lt;mark&gt;the social media&lt;&#x2F;mark&gt;.
The moment you stop interacting with them in real like, poof they are the happiest people on earth.
Yet, nobody is happy in this beautiful place &lt;code&gt;#nature&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#mother_earth&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;code&gt;#savetheplanet&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.
Everyone has a problem to share and nobody wants a do what it takes (or get help) to solve their problem.
(&lt;em&gt;Ironically, this sentence proves that I am a &quot;man&quot;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, As our world is getting to a point that a piece of glass is how we understand people,
(&lt;em&gt;Both, the people we meet in real life and the people we &quot;meet&quot; in the magic mirror.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)
we are moving away from our own identity in nature, the feeling of knowing the things(&lt;em&gt;especially people&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) we interact with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The another problem is the ability to ignore(&lt;em&gt;in other words, run away from interactions and confrontations&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)
is supercharged by an arrangement of rocks that can think.
(&lt;em&gt;thinking about it, we too are arrangements of rocks that can think, but you get the point.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p class=&quot;alert-title&quot;&gt;Note&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;This is a checkpoint, congratulations! You have successfully read to x% of this story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were always attention seekers to begin with,
but now our attention span is so bad that we need to be doing something to do something.
I myself am addicted to the glowing box that I subconsciously(&lt;em&gt;umm, actually, mindlessly*&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) pick it up
and do something on it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;something &#x2F;sŭm′thĭng&#x2F;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Pronoun:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I do not know what&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I do not remember what&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;caution&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p class=&quot;alert-title&quot;&gt;Caution&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;I was so invested in arranging the meaning of something, that I forgot what I was writing about,
the story below is after 5 minutes of reading what I wrote from top to this point.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Where were we? Yes! &quot;Attention span&quot;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) We(&lt;em&gt;I?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) have lost our(&lt;em&gt;my&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) abilty to focus.
We need something to stimulate us all the time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time table is something like this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#282828;color:#fdf4c1aa;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;Wake Up: Yay, new video from &amp;quot;xyz&amp;quot;! I can’t wait to see what they’ve posted overnight.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Morning Routine: Scroll through the news. Gotta stay updated on current events!
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Exercise: Listen to a podcast while I’m at it. It makes the workout feel shorter and more productive.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Freshen Up: I can’t bathe without listening to some music. It sets the mood and makes the routine enjoyable.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Breakfast: Did anyone post something interesting? Maybe I’ll share my breakfast too!
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Commute to Work&#x2F;School: It’s so hard to find good music.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Work&#x2F;School: Slides, slides, slides, ahah! PDF overload!.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mid-Morning Break: I need a quick TikTok break. These videos are so funny.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lunch: Scrolling through Instagram while I eat.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Afternoon Slump: I need a boost! Time for a quick game on my phone to recharge my brain.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Back from School: How is someone, let’s call them? I need to catch up on the latest gossip! Let’s text them.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Evening Activities: Watching a new series on Netflix while scrolling through social media. Multitasking is key!
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dinner: I’ll put on a YouTube video while I eat.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Post-Dinner: Time for a quick scroll through Twitter. I need to see what’s trending today!
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;In Bed: Can’t sleep without white noise. I need that sound to drown out the silence and help me drift off.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Before Sleep: Just one last scroll through social media.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we never know when the thing we despise becomes a short break, then a habit and finally the ultimate form: addiction.
I mean I hate social media, and yet I find myself endlessly scrolling and while still being aware of it multiple times a day.
My excuse to it for myself is: I love technology, I am pursuing a career in it and well this is a part of it, it is how I become
up to date to the things I need to know. Otherwise, I will be behind this race(&lt;em&gt;Basically FOMO&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). Sometimes I try to focus on
only things that I think matters and control myself of being overly simulated and the next day(&lt;em&gt;withdrawls start&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) all night scroll compensating
the day before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;warning&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p class=&quot;alert-title&quot;&gt;Warning&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Do not just take this story as fiction. Ignorance in this case, isn&#x27;t bliss.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish &quot;living&quot; was simple, talking to people was simple, sharing your views was simple, sharing achievements (&lt;em&gt;showing off&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) was simple, sharing pain was simple; but nothing is.
I am an introvert, I have no friends, I have no one to talk to, I am not what people expect; all these feeling hit everyone at least once
in our lives but the problem is that mostly they all hit at once(&lt;em&gt;Could it, be.. any worse?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;code&gt;#chandler&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;).
But, it seems that this is normal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each generation perceives life differently. The entire perspective of life seen by our grandparents is different from our parents and is different from how we perceive the world and I wonder the tension of views it creates when all the generations with their own good perspective of the world are together in the same place(&lt;em&gt;imagine them living in the same place&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A grandchild disagreeing to both their father&#x2F;mother&#x27;s and grandparent&#x27;s way of thinking (&lt;em&gt;In this sentence, all three generations can be permuted to any place.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) is the best way to create hate amongst family members. This is why, living alone and meeting people only during special occasions works best to have a healthy family. (&lt;em&gt;&quot;I guess&quot;, because I haven&#x27;t scientifically collected the data to say it with confdence.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tip&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p class=&quot;alert-title&quot;&gt;Tip&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Assume that you are reading the mind of a person who is struggling to write what they want to write. That way this story feels more natural.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We humans are the superior animals because we can reason, then change and adapt. You might argue that other animals change and adapt too, but the adaptation they go through is from natural selection not through intelligence. Yet, to change from what we are currently to what we want to be is a very energy consuming process and evolutionarily we are built to save our energy which prevents us from changing from what we are(&lt;em&gt;yes, we have been evolved to be lazy and it is inhuman(inanimal?) to not be lazy, beat that excuse the next time someone calls you lazy.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;jokes aside&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The best thing that we humans can do is change and adapt and know that it is worth it to use the enery to change our nature. And the point of this story is there is no point
&lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;in being arrogant and believing in something so badly that you can not change how you see it&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Relative Happiness</title>
        <published>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/relative-happiness/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/relative-happiness/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/relative-happiness/">&lt;p&gt;Happiness can be faked, I guess. Because, It means two things. The happiness that you think that you feel, and the happiness that others think that you feel. And yeah, It is easy to say, &quot;If you&#x27;re not happy, just be happy!&quot; to a person when you in your mind think that you are happy yourself. When you are happy, it is easy to assume that others are happy too (&lt;em&gt;or others can be happy too&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). But as all things science, everything that you see or feel isn&#x27;t true. It is more difficult to believe if someone is happy if you yourself do think that you are not happy. Speaking as a person who used this (&lt;em&gt;&quot;If you&#x27;re not happy, just be happy!&quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Sentence quite often (&lt;em&gt;well I am a professional here, having experienced both happiness and unhappiness&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), I genuinely believed that you can just think that you&#x27;re happy, then bam! You&#x27;ll be happy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, apparently it is far difficult to &quot;fake happiness until you make happiness&quot; when you are in a state of &quot;unhappiness&quot; yourself. That makes me think that there are two kinds of happiness. One will be the temporary (at the moment) happiness, and another will be persistent (most of the time) happiness. You seem to be feeling happy when you do something that makes you happy (&lt;em&gt;like, watching a movie or writing whatever you want and calling it a story when it clearly isn&#x27;t&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) which is the temporary happiness. And the persistent happiness or unhappiness in this case is that constant reminder of your brain calling a moment happy because every other moment other than that moment means not being happy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Ooh! Chest pains!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Yeah, it is complex when you really think about it, but when you&#x27;re really happy you don&#x27;t think about being happy. Well, this mild surge of unhappiness that I am feeling might have caused by me not being able to reach their expectations or they not being to reach my expectations or both or none(&lt;em&gt;because I think I am forcing myself to be happy for a million reasons to be happy but failing to be happy, hence this &quot;story&quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). But, see? The main source of happiness is unhappiness itself (&lt;em&gt;bravo! Consolidating yourself!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) and well if you&#x27;re unhappy now, you are destined to be happy after this session of unhappiness ends (&lt;em&gt;hah! The path to happiness&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, since you have read till the end, you might have grasped the very concept of happiness (&lt;em&gt;or unhappiness&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), but (&lt;em&gt;hahaha &quot;butt&quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) if you by any means take this seriously and somehow got into an unending rabbithole of unhappiness (&lt;em&gt;or happiness (&lt;strong&gt;equally dangerous (&lt;em&gt;haha brackets inside brackets inside brackets (parenthesis?)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; ) that is not to be blamed to me. I mean just because I had some fun ending doesn&#x27;t mean it is not a serous writing and I wish that you (&lt;em&gt;if you, a reader exist (&lt;strong&gt;I think it is just me who reads my blog&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) read it seriously but after all this is my blog and I can say (&lt;em&gt;or write, duhh!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) anything I want here and the best advice I can give is do not believe everything you see in the internet (&lt;em&gt;or outer net, unless it is proven science because everything else is a human construct and can change to make a human happy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Life in a Box</title>
        <published>2024-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/life-in-a-box/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/life-in-a-box/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/life-in-a-box/">&lt;p&gt;The days are getting weirder. I think that I am living in a 2D world more than in the 3D world. Here, everything is boxes. Square, squircle, rectangle, rounded rectangle and what not. Not that I am living in a high-tech society where everything is managed by glowing square and rectangle boxes but, my interest in tech and keeping up with it as much as I can have enclosed me in these glowing rectangles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the first thing you do when you wake up in the morning? Drink water? Go to the bathroom? Let me tell you what I am doing. I search for my phone as soon as my eyes are opened in the morning. That is pretty messed up. These boxes have become so involved in my life that I can sense that I am not carrying one around. It feels like I have forgotten to drink water or something similar.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During high usage these boxes don&#x27;t have very useful things to offer as well, most of the things are just dopamine inducing content that makes you feel like you have laughed or learned something, but it only lasts until the next video starts. But I still shift from one box to another. From my phone to my laptop and then my TV and back to my phone, my life is roaming around.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that it only has negatives, from talking to our loved ones to sharing what you have learned to sharing the thoughts that come to your head, everything is done within the boxes, and it is faster and easier too. Even &quot;social interaction&quot; is a term that in lies inside the glowing boxes nowadays. Perhaps too much of anything is always bad, and &quot;everything&quot; includes the glowing boxes too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of these boxes, apparently the generations are divided by the tech literacy than by time. The behaviors of &quot;Millennial&quot; living in a developed country where tech adoption is fast may be similar to the &quot;Generation Z&quot; living in a developing country where tech adoption is slow or the family who&#x27;s tech adoption is slow.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a Gen Z myself. Though, I have grown in the age of iPhone and Facebook. I was only introduced to these after 2013 and so were my parents. This makes me feel too young, but Windows 11 was the OS that I used for the first time in my home computer. Though that was the OS when we bought the laptop after I enabled beta updates as soon as I got it because of the &quot;techie&quot; I was, and the second day Linux was my main OS, and it has been the same since then. And since everything I watch and everyone I follow are Millennial Tech Geeks, I have become to be this way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The glowing boxes and keeping up with the latest tech news has made me who I am, but the influence of the people who are privacy focused and whom I follow has made me hesitant about things like &quot;proprietary software&quot; and &quot;big tech&quot;. Though it is a good thing, I hesitate to try out new things as they come out. It&#x27;s a dilemma that there is so much to learn in the world of boxes, but there is also a happier and healthier world to learn about and live in. Only if there was a way to merge the two, which seems more disastrous as I now think about it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do I manage my life in these glowing boxes and my life outside? No, I am not writing about how I manage my life (lives?). I am asking you. It is a very difficult thing to do as a student with all his resources in the form of videos and PDFs. &lt;strong&gt;I conclude that self-control is the most essential skill a human needs, and what I need to do is to develop it anyhow.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; A simple &#x27;ping&#x27; or &#x27;ring&#x27; should not make me go and pick up a box to eventually get me to doom-scrolling. How&#x27;s your life like in a box?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Time Travelling With You</title>
        <published>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/time-travelling-with-you/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/time-travelling-with-you/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/time-travelling-with-you/">&lt;p&gt;We have this plan, and it&#x27;s on my mind for a very long time. Some alone time together, far from this prejudicial society with its mythical norms. A cheat day when we break most of the &quot;said&quot; norms of the society and experience a liberal feeling. Rebels they&#x27;ll call but, we would not care about what they say.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would be scared to write this, I have always been scared to change things up and go beyond, until you held my hand and taught to be myself, taught how I could make the things I wanted to be true, true. One can only learn by experience they said, I learned mostly from your experiences, from the mistakes you made you&#x27;d teach me, from new steps you took you&#x27;d teach me. You&#x27;d listen to me and comment on my thoughts, scold me and still let me be myself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few steps ahead you&#x27;d walk, showing directions and alerting me with the obstacles I&#x27;m about to face, like a mother who would taste the food herself before feeding it to her baby. I could share most of what I feel to you, and you&#x27;d have an answer to each. This day, every year you take me back to the past. A past with no judgement, a past I want to relive, recreate with you, and I am sure that we will do it someday.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully in the near future, we will travel back to that past.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Life, Love, Twilight and a Butterfly</title>
        <published>2023-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/life-love-twilight-and-a-butterfly/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/life-love-twilight-and-a-butterfly/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/life-love-twilight-and-a-butterfly/">&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve seen life in terms of science. Always tend to prefer science&#x27;s explanation better than any reasoning one might give to life. Because it makes sense. The relief of knowing the end. Believing in what might happen in the last moments. My preferred answers to all the things is scientific, that gives me the relief that it&#x27;ll be true most of the time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet science fails sometimes. The tried, and tested methods might not be applicable, something that happens regularly doesn&#x27;t make it true. Consciously and subconsciously, I am still speaking of what science has proven. It has proven itself to be wrong most of the time. That, something should not be thought as one universal truth, but rather a possible truth for the current instance of time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking outside the window, hearing the barking dogs, the sky is cloudy and it&#x27;s mildly raining. The streetlights are glowing everywhere, though it&#x27;s a moonless night, the world is still bright with life. The world around me is sleeping, it&#x27;s silent, I can hear each raindrop individually, the insects chirping, the wind and my heartbeat. A mosquito is flying around me, with its own goals, to get food, to get energy, to continue itself and preserve its kind. I have a different goal, to kill the mosquito and sleep well. Life&#x27;s keeping us both alive and awake in this night when everyone is sleeping and consciously dead. Everything is keeping me awake. Myself, the mosquito, the weather, the light outside my house, my phone and many unknown unknowns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve read self-help books, I&#x27;ve watched a lot of talks about achievements and ideas and life, and I get inspired by it. But it doesn&#x27;t last long. Newton&#x27;s first law of motion said, &quot;An object at rest tends to remain at rest, and a moving object tends to remain in motion in a straight line with constant speed.&quot; Similarly, I tend to remain in the same state of what I am despite being motivated for some time. This whole analogy is faulty because scientifically an object in motion tends to remain in motion in a straight path, unless an external force acts on it. So, technically the reads and talks should have been impacting the whole trajectory of my life, and I surely can say that It hasn&#x27;t impacted enough to make a difference. The self-help books truly were written for self-help, their own self, like I am writing this piece right now for myself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you&#x27;ll never know the correct answer. It&#x27;s fine to not know something, it&#x27;s fine to not know anything but, the realization that you will never know something is devastating. It&#x27;s the feeling of realization that you will never be able to get the thing you wished for. Life changes stories, one changes dreams, like science changes its truth over time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some sleepless nights can get you what you want, others just take life away a tad faster. This one is the latter, the one that has no meaning, there&#x27;s no achievement, it&#x27;s just an unhealthy sleepless night. I need to sleep, I feel like sleeping, sleeping until a new day arrives, a whole new life waiting for me to sleep, so it can get to me even faster.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have explained life in different ways, how love fills it with joy, how having a friend makes it a lot easier to live, how some achievement may make you want to live a bit more. But I particularly like the way nature has taught us. If you cut the cocoon of a butterfly to let it come out of it easily, giving it love and all the care you could give, it will die, not being able to flap its wings, unable to take a flight, unable to live a life, unable to figure out things, unable to find a way to contribute to the world, unable to find a way to live longer and never getting the chance to bring more life like its own to the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loving an unborn butterfly is cruel, and loving a flying butterfly is stupid. One can only admire its beauty seeing it roam around the flowers, living dodging and ducking the predators and finding its own world to live, a life it wanted, not a life you wanted it to have, not a life you thought would be better, not a life with you and your unintentionally cruel love.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Who He Was</title>
        <published>2022-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/who-he-was/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/who-he-was/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/who-he-was/">&lt;p&gt;He had lived a life of a villagen; who was neither a villager nor a citizen. He was seen as a citizen by his village friends and a villager by his city friends. To his view he was a citizen as he lived in a town for studying and went to his village if there was a holiday of any sort.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because of that he knew the customs of the both worlds. The tradition and behaviours of village as well as the city had moulded him and his behaviours, as he wanted to be treated as native by both of his friend groups.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;village&quot;&gt;Village:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid he would take goats for grazing, climb trees, run down the hill to the river, played with mud and sticks, football made up of clothes stuffed inside a sock, fly kites, slide in coconut leaves, made wheels by cutting slippers soles and run assuming they were cars or bikes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his teens he would still go to the village where his grandparents lived farming, ploughing and growing stuff. But he would not get a chance to experience how all those things were done. He&#x27;d sit as an outsider and watch them plough the field, controlling and turning bulls at their command and made them drag the plough on the filed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They worried about him and his nice, clean clothes and would ask him to stay far from the field and not get dirty. He wore his dad&#x27;s old clothes and went to the field sometimes, but they still wouldn&#x27;t give him a chance to work, saying he&#x27;d get hurt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;city&quot;&gt;City:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While he was in the city, he&#x27;d play snake on his dad&#x27;s Nokia and watch cartoons like Ben 10, Pokémon, Bakugan, Dragon Ball Z, Tom and Jerry, Moo min, Zig and Sharko, etc on TV.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His dad got a smarter but still keypad phone (Nokia X1) which had internet, and he made his first Facebook account in it. He would download Java games like Assassin&#x27;s Creed, Spider-Man, Ben 10, Mario, Diamond Rush etc from Waptrick. When bored he would dig through the deepest settings of the phone and change things, which might have planted his love for computers at that time, and he still does it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&#x27;d often go to his friend&#x27;s house and watch them play with their PSPs and Computers. He was always fascinated by how those things worked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here his friends would not let him play with their PSPs and Computers as he didn&#x27;t know how to use them, and they were afraid if he would break it. As smartphones were at the market, his uncle gifted his mom with a Samsung Smartphone, and he played offline games like Temple Run, Mario, Plant vs Zombies, etc in it. The mobile data costs were high at that time and that has an effect on him till today; he doesn&#x27;t play online games.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;influence&quot;&gt;Influence&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He knew things of both village and town and even the teachers who taught them about primitive technologies and  other old things would be shocked by seeing him recognize everything they read from the book since he had seen them being used. He taught his friends to communicate secretly by the special language he learnt at the village (basically it was putting a special syllable before every syllable and speaking it that way. The special syllable was &quot;cha&quot; and the word &#x27;development&#x27; would be &quot;cha-dev cha-lop cha-ment&quot; but in our native language of course.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&#x27;d teach his village friends to make a Facebook account, upload posts, download games on their phones and all that &quot;techy stuff&quot; they thought was magic. He shared downloaded movies and music to them. He was a tech guy to everyone there. He still gets calls from his relatives if any kind of mobile related problems occur to them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is surely due to limited resources, He would use everything by pushing it to the limits. Still today, he digs through the settings of a newer looking phone, hoping he&#x27;d find new interesting stuff.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was never a native and that made him unique which he still enjoys being.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;today&quot;&gt;Today&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today he went to his village for a visit, and was devastated by the collapsing old house as it is abandoned and nobody cares for it. He got one day to recall all memories he spent as a child and also a teen. One day of sitting on the floor eating with hands in a smokey warm kitchen with food grown in the kitchen garden or rather &quot;kitchen field&quot; with no added chemicals. One day of eating fruits by picking it himself from the tree. One day of gazing at the stars shining brightly above the heaven below. One day of wishing to meet his old friends who mostly are now abroad for money. All those memories to come back melting the heart and eyes of who he was, me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Nostalgia - My first Love</title>
        <published>2021-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/paru/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/paru/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/paru/">&lt;p&gt;~ To Paru&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more I think about it, the more it becomes clear that you are the most loving and my favorite person. I remember those days in Bhirgaun and gulp thinking those days were too good and will not return back. I think about how we played hide and seek, made temples under the flower bush and get overwhelmed by the warmth it brings to my heart. I remember how we played;  you being teacher and I being a student  , you being my mother and I being your son , you being my wife and I being your husband. I remember sleeping on your lap while you played with my hair. I still remember you as that little girl who herself is scared but catches my hand to comfort me while I was scared of the imaginary ghosts from the stories told by Sudip. I remember coming to your house and staying the night talking to you when I didn&#x27;t get a phone to use WI-FI. I remember being compared to you as we were on same grade and I didn&#x27;t get top three position on exam while you stood first.I remember everytime I met you I kissed you on your cheeks and you wiped it. I remember you being angry and scolding me and the next minute we were talking about how we liked each other. I remember you skipping to another grade and actually being senior to me (You wouldn&#x27;t know how angry I was that day.). I remember you leaving Dharan and being far from me when we didn&#x27;t even had WIFI to communicate. I remember being lonely and sad when I went to your house and you weren&#x27;t there (I still do).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since those Days we may be far from each other but I still love you the most . I still think about you and want you to call me, let me sleep on your lap and want you play with my hair while we share our stories , I want you to shout at me when I make mistakes and hit my stupid head while I irritate you with my weird interests. I am what I am because you were already in this world when I just came. Not every birthday can be special but some birthdays can. I want you to feel special  today because today is the day I love the most (even though I don&#x27;t remember the date).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this capsule I make my most special person more special by making you the  first person in the world to get a birthday wish from this protocol.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With love,
~ Spu&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The End</title>
        <published>2021-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/the-end/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/the-end/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/the-end/">&lt;p&gt;I am and will be yours and you are mine until the end. We are one single person, and will always be. Will never ever break apart. I vow to never leave you in your darkest times as well as mine. I will always be there with you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I in this dark quiet place. Silence everywhere, why can&#x27;t I feel my heart beating ? Why the soil is not making any sound as I walk in it. Why is nobody here! Hello!!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s been days, maybe weeks , why don&#x27;t I feel any hunger, thirst, not even tiredness. Am I alive or am I not? What&#x27;s that light over there ? Hello!!!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flash!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can&#x27;t I touch you? Why do you look soo old? Why is that bulb glowing soo white instead of yellow? Is that a calendar? It&#x27;s been 10 years? Where are all the photos of mine? Is that your diary? What do you mean you waited?
What is that mark on your neck? It looks like a healed cut.
Hello???!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn&#x27;t a hallucination? So, am I actually dead? Why am I seeing her? And who&#x27;s that guy? Heyy!!, can anyone hear me!!? I&#x27;m up here! Wait, Are they kissing? How am I suddenly able to read minds?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has gone through too much. She attempted suicide? Oh, that&#x27;s what the mark is. So, she met him two years ago on the same graveyard where I was buried.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He too knows what it feels to lose a loved one. His girlfriend died of brain tumor. Ohh so, he plays guitar too. Ahh those good old days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, what have I become? What am I now? What is the purpose of my existence? Maybe there&#x27;s no reason at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I just a part of me that lives in her. Maybe this is my life after I am dead. I&#x27;m an infection inside her brain, the infection that has the ability to form into a tumor. I have the potential to kill her and maybe, maybe we can be together again, should I? But, what&#x27;s life then? Isn&#x27;t it the hope of being alive and trying to fulfill your dreams? What&#x27;s life without some pain, some wounds, some scratches and bruises that makes you feel more alive. She got the opportunity to live it the way it was intended, I didn&#x27;t. Yeah she is actually alive, the aliveness
that comes killing the pain, healing the wounds as the tears dry up. She&#x27;s alive, alive with new hope, with new feelings, a new start.
As she heals from her never-known disease , me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A Man Whose Heart Wasn&#x27;t Broken</title>
        <published>2020-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              scientiac
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://scientiac.space/blog/a-man-whose-heart-wasnt-broken/"/>
        <id>https://scientiac.space/blog/a-man-whose-heart-wasnt-broken/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://scientiac.space/blog/a-man-whose-heart-wasnt-broken/">&lt;p&gt;A wise old man once said and I quote,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;She didn&#x27;t break my heart, she just made me very sad that my dopamine levels got very low. The only thing that could help to increase my dopamine and serotonin levels was to eat food. Excessive intake of so called &quot;Tasty&quot; food containing excess amount of saturated fat and cholesterol caused plaques to build up in my arteries.
Due to the buildup of plaque, my arteries started to narrow down, decreasing the blood flow to my heart. The reduced blood flow caused chest pain, shortness of breath and other problems. Days passed by, but the plaque gradually went on increasing. One day I woke up and found out that I was unconscious for 2 days. The plaque had completely blocked one of my arteries. I had a heart attack . She didn&#x27;t break my heart but she gave me a heart attack.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was about to ask how the heck was he still alive, but my alarm went off and I woke up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
